III

Anxiety in High Places

“Quite so, my dear fellow, quite so,” said Lord Caterham.

He had used the same words three times already, each time in the hope that they would end the interview and permit him to escape. He disliked very much being forced to stand on the steps of the exclusive London club to which he belonged and listen to the interminable eloquence of the Hon. George Lomax.

Clement Edward Alistair Brent, ninth Marquis of Caterham, was a small gentleman, shabbily dressed, and entirely unlike the popular conception of a Marquis. He had faded blue eyes, a thin melancholy nose, and a vague but courteous manner.

The principal misfortune of Lord Caterham’s life was to have succeeded his brother, the eighth Marquis, four years ago. For the previous Lord Caterham had been a man of mark, a household word all over England. At one time Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, he had always bulked largely in the counsels of the Empire, and his country seat, Chimneys, was famous for its hospitality. Ably seconded by his wife, a daughter of the Duke of Perth, history had been made and unmade at informal weekend parties at Chimneys, and there was hardly anyone of note in England—or indeed in Europe—who had not, at one time or another, stayed there.

That was all very well. The ninth Marquis of Caterham had the utmost respect and esteem for the memory of his brother. Henry had done that kind of thing magnificently. What Lord Caterham objected to was the assumption that he was bound to follow in his brother’s footsteps, and that Chimneys was a national possession rather than a private country house. There was nothing that bored Lord Caterham more than politics—unless it was politicians. Hence his impatience under the continued eloquence of George Lomax. A robust man, George Lomax, inclined to embonpoint, with a red face and protuberant eyes, and an immense sense of his own importance.

“You see the point, Caterham? We can’t—we simply can’t afford a scandal of any kind just now. The position is one of the utmost delicacy.”

“It always is,” said Lord Caterham, with a flavour of irony.

“My dear fellow, I’m in a position to know!”

“Oh, quite so, quite so,” said Lord Caterham, falling back upon his previous line of defence.

“One slip over this Herzoslovakian business and we’re done. It is most important that the Oil concessions should be granted to a British company. You must see that?”

“Of course, of course.”

“Prince Michael Obolovitch arrives the end of the week, and the whole thing can be carried through at Chimneys under the guise of a shooting party.”

“I was thinking of going abroad this week,” said Lord Caterham.

“Nonsense, my dear Caterham, no one goes abroad in early October.”

“My doctor seems to think I’m in rather a bad way,” said Lord Caterham, eyeing a taxi that was crawling past with longing eyes.

He was quite unable to make a dash for liberty, however, since Lomax had the unpleasant habit of retaining a hold upon a person with whom he was engaged in serious conversation—doubtless the result of long experience. In this case, he had a firm grip of the lapel of Lord Caterham’s coat.

“My dear man, I put it to you imperially. In a moment of national crisis, such as is fast approaching—”

Lord Caterham wriggled uneasily. He felt suddenly that he would rather give any number of house parties than listen to George Lomax quoting from one of his own speeches. He knew by experience that Lomax was quite capable of going on for twenty minutes without a stop.

“All right,” he said hastily, “I’ll do it. You’ll arrange the whole thing, I suppose.”

“My dear fellow, there’s nothing to arrange. Chimneys, quite apart from its historic associations, is ideally situated. I shall be at the Abbey, less than seven miles away. It wouldn’t do, of course, for me to be actually a member of the house party.”

“Of course not,” agreed Lord Caterham, who had no idea why it would not do, and was not interested to learn.

“Perhaps you wouldn’t mind having Bill Eversleigh, though. He’d be useful to run messages.”

“Delighted,” said Lord Caterham, with a shade more animation. “Bill’s quite a decent shot, and Bundle likes him.”

“The shooting, of course, is not really important. It’s only the pretext, as it were.”

Lord Caterham looked depressed again.

“That will be all, then. The prince, his suite, Bill Eversleigh, Herman Isaacstein—”

“Who?”

“Herman Isaacstein. The representative of the syndicate I spoke to you about.”

“The all-British syndicate?”

“Yes. Why?”

“Nothing—nothing—I only wondered, that’s all. Curious names these people have.”

“Then, of course, there ought to be one or two outsiders—just to give the thing a bona fide appearance. Lady Eileen could see to that—young people, uncritical, and with no idea of politics.”

“Bundle would attend to that all right, I’m sure.”

“I wonder now.” Lomax seemed struck by an idea. “You remember the matter I was speaking about just now?”

“You’ve been speaking about so many things.”

“No, no, I mean this unfortunate contretemps”—he lowered his voice to a mysterious whisper—“the memoirs—Count Stylptitch’s memoirs.”

“I think you’re wrong about that,” said Lord Caterham, suppressing a yawn. “People like scandal. Damn it all, I read reminiscences myself—and enjoy ’em too.”

“The point is not whether people will read them or not—they’ll read them fast enough—but their publication at this juncture might ruin everything—everything. The people of Herzoslovakia wish to restore the monarchy, and are prepared to offer the crown to Prince Michael who has the support and encouragement of His Majesty’s Government—”

“And who is prepared to grant concessions to Mr. Ikey Hermanstein & Co. in return for the loan of a million or so to set him on the throne—”

“Caterham, Caterham,” implored Lomax in an agonized whisper. “Discretion, I beg of you. Above all things, discretion.”

“And the point is,” continued Lord Caterham, with some relish, though he lowered his voice in obedience to the other’s appeal, “that some of Stylptitch’s reminiscences may upset the apple cart. Tyranny and misbehaviour of the Obolovitch family generally, eh? Questions asked in the House. Why replace the present broad-minded and democratic form of Government by an obsolete tyranny? Policy dictated by the bloodsucking Capitalists. Down with the Government. That kind of thing—eh?”

Lomax nodded.

“And there might be worse still,” he breathed. “Suppose—only suppose that some reference should be made to—to that unfortunate disappearance—you know what I mean.”

Lord Caterham stared at him.

“No, I don’t. What disappearance?”

“You must have heard of it? Why, it happened while they were at Chimneys. Henry was terribly upset about it. It almost ruined his career.”

“You interest me enormously,” said Lord Caterham. “Who or what disappeared?”

Lomax leant forward and put his mouth to Lord Caterham’s ear. The latter withdrew it hastily.

“For God’s sake, don’t hiss at me.”

“You heard what I said?”

“Yes, I did,” said Lord Caterham reluctantly. “I remember now hearing something about it at the time. Very curious affair. I wonder who did it. It was never recovered?”

“Never. Of course we had to go about the matter with the utmost discretion. No hint of the loss could be allowed to leak out. But Stylptitch was there at the time. He knew something. Not all, but something. We were at loggerheads with him once or twice over the Turkish question. Suppose that in sheer malice he has set the whole thing down for the world to read. Think of the scandal—of the far-reaching results. Everyone would say—why was it hushed up?”

“Of course they would,” said Lord Caterham, with evident enjoyment.

Lomax, whose voice had risen to a high pitch, took a grip on himself.

“I must keep calm,” he murmured. “I must keep calm. But I ask you this, my dear fellow. If he didn’t mean mischief, why did he send the manuscript to London in this roundabout way?”

“It’s odd, certainly. You are sure of your facts?”

“Absolutely. We—er—had our agents in Paris. The memoirs were conveyed away secretly some weeks before his death.”

“Yes, it looks as though there’s something in it,” said Lord Caterham, with the same relish he had displayed before.

“We have found out that they were sent to a man called Jimmy, or James, McGrath, a Canadian at present in Africa.”

“Quite an Imperial affair, isn’t it?” said Lord Caterham cheerily.

“James McGrath is due to arrive by the Granarth Castle tomorrow—Thursday.”

“What are you going to do about it?”

“We shall, of course, approach him at once, point out the possibly serious consequences, and beg him to defer publication of the memoirs for at least a month, and in any case to permit them to be judiciously—er—edited.”

“Supposing that he says ‘No, sir,’ or ‘I’ll goddarned well see you in hell first,’ or something bright and breezy like that?” suggested Lord Caterham.

“That’s just what I’m afraid of,” said Lomax simply. “That’s why it suddenly occurred to me that it might be a good thing to ask him down to Chimneys as well. He’d be flattered, naturally, at being asked to meet Prince Michael, and it might be easier to handle him.”

“I’m not going to do it,” said Lord Caterham hastily. “I don’t get on with Canadians, never did—especially those that have lived much in Africa!”

“You’d probably find him a splendid fellow—a rough diamond, you know.”

“No, Lomax. I put my foot down there absolutely. Somebody else has got to tackle him.”

“It has occurred to me,” said Lomax, “that a woman might be very useful here. Told enough and not too much, you understand. A woman could handle the whole thing delicately and with tact—put the position before him, as it were, without getting his back up. Not that I approve of women in politics—St. Stephen’s is ruined, absolutely ruined, nowadays. But woman in her own sphere can do wonders. Look at Henry’s wife and what she did for him. Marcia was magnificent, unique, a perfect political hostess.”

“You don’t want me to ask Marcia down for this party, do you?” asked Lord Caterham faintly, turning a little pale at the mention of his redoubtable sister-in-law.

“No, no, you misunderstand me. I was speaking of the influence of women in general. No, I suggest a young woman, a woman of charm, beauty, intelligence?”

“Not Bundle? Bundle would be no use at all. She’s a red-hot socialist if she’s anything at all, and she’d simply scream with laughter at the suggestion.”

“I was not thinking of Lady Eileen. Your daughter, Caterham, is charming, simply charming, but quite a child. We need someone with savoir faire, poise, knowledge of the world—Ah, of course, the very person. My cousin Virginia.”

“Mrs. Revel?” Lord Caterham brightened up. He began to feel that he might possibly enjoy the party after all. “A very good suggestion of yours, Lomax. The most charming woman in London.”

“She is well up in Herzoslovakian affairs too. Her husband was at the Embassy there, you remember. And, as you say, a woman of great personal charm.”

“A delightful creature,” murmured Lord Caterham.

“That is settled, then.”

Mr. Lomax relaxed his hold on Lord Caterham’s lapel, and the latter was quick to avail himself of the chance.

“Bye-bye, Lomax, you’ll make all the arrangements, won’t you.”

He dived into a taxi. As far as it is possible for one upright Christian gentleman to dislike another upright Christian gentleman, Lord Caterham disliked the Hon. George Lomax. He disliked his puffy red face, his heavy breathing, and his prominent blue eyes. He thought of the coming week and sighed. A nuisance, an abominable nuisance. Then he thought of Virginia Revel and cheered up a little.

“A delightful creature,” he murmured to himself. “A most delightful creature.”

XXII

The Red Signal

Superintendent Battle was standing in the library at Wyvern Abbey.

George Lomax, seated before a desk overflowing with papers, was frowning portentously.

Superintendent Battle had opened proceedings by making a brief and businesslike report. Since then, the conversation had lain almost entirely with George, and Battle had contented himself with making brief and usually monosyllabic replies to the other‚Äôs questions.

On the desk, in front of George, was the packet of letters Anthony had found on his dressing-table.

‚ÄúI can‚Äôt understand it at all,‚Äù said George irritably, as he picked up the packet. ‚ÄúThey‚Äôre in code, you say?‚Äù

‚ÄúJust so, Mr.¬ÝLomax.‚Äù

‚ÄúAnd where does he say he found them‚ÅÝ‚Äîon his dressing-table?‚Äù

Battle repeated, word for word, Anthony Cade‚Äôs account of how he had come to regain possession of the letters.

‚ÄúAnd he brought them at once to you? That was quite proper‚ÅÝ‚Äîquite proper. But who could have placed them in his room?‚Äù

Battle shook his head.

‚ÄúThat‚Äôs the sort of thing you ought to know,‚Äù complained George. ‚ÄúIt sounds to me very fishy‚ÅÝ‚Äîvery fishy indeed. What do we know about this man Cade anyway? He appears in a most mysterious manner‚ÅÝ‚Äîunder highly suspicious circumstances‚ÅÝ‚Äîand we know nothing whatever about him. I may say that I, personally, don‚Äôt care for his manner at all. You‚Äôve made inquiries about him, I suppose?‚Äù

Superintendent Battle permitted himself a patient smile.

‚ÄúWe wired at once to South Africa, and his story has been confirmed on all points. He was in Bulawayo with Mr.¬ÝMcGrath at the time he stated. Previous to their meeting, he was employed by Messrs. Castle, the tourist agents.‚Äù

‚ÄúJust what I should have expected,‚Äù said George. ‚ÄúHe has the kind of cheap assurance that succeeds in a certain type of employment. But about these letters‚ÅÝ‚Äîsteps must be taken at once‚ÅÝ‚Äîat once‚ÅÝ‚Äî‚Äù

The great man puffed himself out and swelled importantly.

Superintendent Battle opened his mouth, but George forestalled him.

‚ÄúThere must be no delay. These letters must be decoded without any loss of time. Let me see, who is the man? There is a man‚ÅÝ‚Äîconnected with the British Museum. Knows all there is to know about ciphers. Ran the department for us during the War. Where is Miss Oscar? She will know. Name something like Win‚ÅÝ‚ÄîWin‚ÅÝ‚Äî‚Äù

‚ÄúProfessor Wynward,‚Äù said Battle.

‚ÄúExactly. I remember perfectly now. He must be wired to, immediately.‚Äù

‚ÄúI have done so, Mr.¬ÝLomax, an hour ago. He will arrive by the 12:10.‚Äù

‚ÄúOh, very good, very good. Thank Heaven, something is off my mind. I shall have to be in town today. You can get along without me, I suppose?‚Äù

‚ÄúI think so, sir.‚Äù

‚ÄúWell, do your best, Battle, do your best. I am terribly rushed just at present.‚Äù

‚ÄúJust so, sir.‚Äù

‚ÄúBy the way, why did not Mr.¬ÝEversleigh come over with you?‚Äù

‚ÄúHe was still asleep, sir. We‚Äôve been up all night, as I told you.‚Äù

‚ÄúOh, quite so. I am frequently up nearly the whole night myself. To do the work of thirty-six hours in twenty-four, that is my constant task! Send Mr.¬ÝEversleigh over at once when you get back, will you, Battle?‚Äù

‚ÄúI will give him your message, sir.‚Äù

‚ÄúThank you, Battle. I realize perfectly that you had to repose a certain amount of confidence in him. But do you think it was strictly necessary to take my cousin, Mrs.¬ÝRevel, into your confidence also?‚Äù

‚ÄúIn view of the name signed to those letters, I do, Mr.¬ÝLomax.‚Äù

‚ÄúAn amazing piece of effrontery,‚Äù murmured George, his brow darkened as he looked at the bundle of letters. ‚ÄúI remember the late king of Herzoslovakia. A charming fellow, but weak‚ÅÝ‚Äîdeplorably weak. A tool in the hands of an unscrupulous woman. Have you any theory as to how these letters came to be restored to Mr.¬ÝCade?‚Äù

‚ÄúIt‚Äôs my opinion,‚Äù said Battle, ‚Äúthat if people can‚Äôt get a thing one way‚ÅÝ‚Äîthey try another.‚Äù

‚ÄúI don‚Äôt quite follow you,‚Äù said George.

‚ÄúThis crook, this King Victor, he‚Äôs well aware by now that the Council Chamber is watched. So he‚Äôll let us have the letters, and let us do the decoding, and let us find the hiding-place. And then‚ÅÝ‚Äîtrouble! But Lemoine and I between us will attend to that.‚Äù

‚ÄúYou‚Äôve got a plan, eh?‚Äù

‚ÄúI wouldn‚Äôt go so far as to say I‚Äôve got a plan. But I‚Äôve got an idea. It‚Äôs a very useful thing sometimes, an idea.‚Äù

Thereupon Superintendent Battle took his departure.

He had no intention of taking George any further into his confidence.

On the way back, he passed Anthony on the road and stopped.

‚ÄúGoing to give me a lift back to the house?‚Äù asked Anthony. ‚ÄúThat‚Äôs good.‚Äù

‚ÄúWhere have you been, Mr.¬ÝCade?‚Äù

‚ÄúDown to the station to inquire about trains.‚Äù

Battle raised his eyebrows.

‚ÄúThinking of leaving us again?‚Äù he inquired.

‚ÄúNot just at present,‚Äù laughed Anthony. ‚ÄúBy the way, what‚Äôs upset Isaacstein? He arrived in the car just as I left, and he looked as though something had given him a nasty jolt.‚Äù

‚ÄúMr.¬ÝIsaacstein?‚Äù

‚ÄúYes.‚Äù

‚ÄúI can‚Äôt say, I‚Äôm sure. I fancy it would take a good deal to jolt him.‚Äù

‚ÄúSo do I,‚Äù agreed Anthony. ‚ÄúHe‚Äôs quite one of the strong silent yellow men of finance.‚Äù

Suddenly Battle leant forward and touched the chauffeur on the shoulder.

‚ÄúStop, will you? And wait for me here.‚Äù

He jumped out of the car, much to Anthony‚Äôs surprise. But in a minute or two, the latter perceived M. Lemoine advancing to meet the English detective, and gathered that it was a signal from him which had attracted Battle‚Äôs attention.

There was a rapid colloquy between them, and then the superintendent returned to the car and jumped in again, biding the chauffeur drive on.

His expression had completely changed.

‚ÄúThey‚Äôve found the revolver,‚Äù he said suddenly and curtly.

‚ÄúWhat?‚Äù

Anthony gazed at him in great surprise.

‚ÄúWhere?‚Äù

‚ÄúIn Isaacstein‚Äôs suitcase.‚Äù

‚ÄúOh, impossible!‚Äù

‚ÄúNothing‚Äôs impossible,‚Äù said Battle. ‚ÄúI ought to have remembered that.‚Äù

He sat perfectly still, tapping his knee with his hand.

‚ÄúWho found it?‚Äù

Battle jerked his head over his shoulder.

‚ÄúLemoine. Clever chap. They think no end of him at the S√ªret√©.‚Äù

‚ÄúBut doesn‚Äôt this upset all your ideas?‚Äù

‚ÄúNo,‚Äù said Superintendent Battle very slowly. ‚ÄúI can‚Äôt say it does. It was a bit of a surprise, I admit, at first. But it fits in very well with one idea of mine.‚Äù

‚ÄúWhich is?‚Äù

But the superintendent branched off on to a totally different subject.

‚ÄúI wonder if you‚Äôd mind finding Mr.¬ÝEversleigh for me, sir? There‚Äôs a message for him from Mr.¬ÝLomax. He‚Äôs to go over to the Abbey at once.‚Äù

‚ÄúAll right,‚Äù said Anthony. The car had just drawn up at the great door. ‚ÄúHe‚Äôs probably in bed still.‚Äù

‚ÄúI think not,‚Äù said the detective. ‚ÄúIf you‚Äôll look, you‚Äôll see him walking under the trees with Mrs.¬ÝRevel.‚Äù

‚ÄúWonderful eyes you have, haven‚Äôt you, Battle?‚Äù said Anthony as he departed on his errand.

He delivered the message to Bill, who was duly disgusted.

‚ÄúDamn it all,‚Äù grumbled Bill to himself, as he strode off to the house, ‚Äúwhy can‚Äôt Codders sometimes leave me alone? And why can‚Äôt these blasted Colonials stay in their Colonies? What do they want to come over here for, and pick out all the best girls? I‚Äôm fed to the teeth with everything.‚Äù

‚ÄúHave you heard about the revolver?‚Äù asked Virginia breathlessly, as Bill left them.

‚ÄúBattle told me. Rather staggering, isn‚Äôt it? Isaacstein was in a frightful state yesterday to get away, but I thought it was just nerves. He‚Äôs about the one person I‚Äôd have pitched upon as being above suspicion. Can you see any motive for his wanting Prince Michael out of the way?‚Äù

‚ÄúIt certainly doesn‚Äôt fit in,‚Äù agreed Virginia thoughtfully.

‚ÄúNothing fits in anywhere,‚Äù said Anthony discontentedly. ‚ÄúI rather fancied myself as an amateur detective to begin with, and so far all I‚Äôve done is to clear the character of the French governess at vast trouble and some little expense.‚Äù

‚ÄúIs that what you went to France for?‚Äù inquired Virginia.

‚ÄúYes, I went to Dinard and had an interview with the Comtesse de Breteuil, awfully pleased with my own cleverness, and fully expecting to be told that no such person as Mademoiselle Brun had ever been heard of. Instead of which I was given to understand that the lady in question had been the mainstay of the household for the last seven years. So, unless the Comtesse is also a crook, that ingenious theory of mine falls to the ground.‚Äù

Virginia shook her head.

‚ÄúMadame de Breteuil is quite above suspicion. I know her quite well, and I fancy I must have come across Mademoiselle at the ch√¢teau. I certainly know her face quite well‚ÅÝ‚Äîin that vague way one does know governesses and companions and people one sits opposite to in trains. It‚Äôs awful, but I never really look at them properly. Do you?‚Äù

‚ÄúOnly if they‚Äôre exceptionally beautiful,‚Äù admitted Anthony.

‚ÄúWell, in this case‚ÅÝ‚Äî‚Äù she broke off. ‚ÄúWhat‚Äôs the matter?‚Äù

Anthony was staring at a figure which detached itself from the clump of trees and stood there rigidly at attention. It was the Herzoslovakian, Boris.

‚ÄúExcuse me,‚Äù said Anthony to Virginia, ‚ÄúI must just speak to my dog a minute.‚Äù

He went across to where Boris was standing.

‚ÄúWhat‚Äôs the matter? What do you want?‚Äù

‚ÄúMaster,‚Äù said Boris, bowing.

‚ÄúYes, that‚Äôs all very well, but you mustn‚Äôt keep following me about like this. It looks odd.‚Äù

Without a word, Boris produced a soiled scrap of paper, evidently torn from a letter, and handed it to Anthony.

‚ÄúWhat‚Äôs this?‚Äù said Anthony.

There was an address scrawled on the paper, nothing else.

‚ÄúHe dropped it,‚Äù said Boris. ‚ÄúI bring it to the Master.‚Äù

‚ÄúWho dropped it?‚Äù

‚ÄúThe foreign gentleman.‚Äù

‚ÄúBut why bring it to me?‚Äù

Boris looked at him reproachfully.

‚ÄúWell, anyway, go away now,‚Äù said Anthony. ‚ÄúI‚Äôm busy.‚Äù

Boris saluted, turned sharply on his heel, and marched away. Anthony rejoined Virginia, thrusting the piece of paper into his pocket.

‚ÄúWhat did he want?‚Äù she asked curiously. ‚ÄúAnd why do you call him your dog?‚Äù

‚ÄúBecause he acts like one,‚Äù said Anthony, answering the last question first. ‚ÄúHe must have been a retriever in his last incarnation, I think. He‚Äôs just brought me a piece of a letter which he says the foreign gentleman dropped. I suppose he means Lemoine.‚Äù

‚ÄúI suppose so,‚Äù acquiesced Virginia.

‚ÄúHe‚Äôs always following me round,‚Äù continued Anthony. ‚ÄúJust like a dog. Says next to nothing. Just looks at me with his big round eyes. I can‚Äôt make him out.‚Äù

‚ÄúPerhaps he meant Isaacstein,‚Äù suggested Virginia. ‚ÄúIsaacstein looks foreign enough, Heaven knows.‚Äù

‚ÄúIsaacstein,‚Äù muttered Anthony impatiently. ‚ÄúWhere the devil does he come in?‚Äù

‚ÄúAre you ever sorry that you‚Äôve mixed yourself up in all this?‚Äù asked Virginia suddenly.

‚ÄúSorry? Good Lord, no. I love it. I‚Äôve spent most of my life looking for trouble, you know. Perhaps, this time, I‚Äôve got a little more than I bargained for.‚Äù

‚ÄúBut you‚Äôre well out of the wood now,‚Äù said Virginia, a little surprised by the unusual gravity of his tone.

‚ÄúNot quite.‚Äù

They strolled on for a minute or two in silence.

‚ÄúThere are some people,‚Äù said Anthony, breaking the silence, ‚Äúwho don‚Äôt conform to the signals. An ordinary well-regulated locomotive slows down or pulls up when it sees the red light hoisted against it. Perhaps I was born colourblind. When I see the red signal‚ÅÝ‚ÄîI can‚Äôt help forging ahead. And in the end, you know, that spells disaster. Bound to. And quite right really. That sort of thing is bad for traffic generally.‚Äù

He still spoke very seriously.

‚ÄúI suppose,‚Äù said Virginia, ‚Äúthat you have taken a good many risks in your life?‚Äù

‚ÄúPretty nearly every one there is‚ÅÝ‚Äîexcept marriage.‚Äù

‚ÄúThat‚Äôs rather cynical.‚Äù

‚ÄúIt wasn‚Äôt meant to be. Marriage, the kind of marriage I mean, would be the biggest adventure of the lot.‚Äù

‚ÄúI like that,‚Äù said Virginia, flushing eagerly.

‚ÄúThere‚Äôs only one kind of woman I‚Äôd want to marry‚ÅÝ‚Äîthe kind who is worlds removed from my type of life. What would we do about it? Is she to lead my life, or am I to lead hers?‚Äù

‚ÄúIf she loved you‚ÅÝ‚Äî‚Äù

‚ÄúSentimentality, Mrs.¬ÝRevel. You know it is. Love isn‚Äôt a drug that you take to blind you to your surroundings‚ÅÝ‚Äîyou can make it that, yes, but it‚Äôs a pity‚ÅÝ‚Äîlove can be a lot more than that. What do you think the king and his beggar maid thought of married life after they‚Äôd been married a year or two? Didn‚Äôt she regret her rags and her bare feet and her carefree life? You bet she did. Would it have been any good renouncing his crown for her sake? Not a bit of good, either. He‚Äôd have made a damned bad beggar, I‚Äôm sure. And no woman respects a man when he‚Äôs doing a thing thoroughly badly.‚Äù

‚ÄúHave you fallen in love with a beggar maid, Mr.¬ÝCade?‚Äù inquired Virginia softly.

‚ÄúIt‚Äôs the other way about with me, but the principle‚Äôs the same.‚Äù

‚ÄúAnd there‚Äôs no way out?‚Äù asked Virginia.

‚ÄúThere‚Äôs always a way out,‚Äù said Anthony gloomily. ‚ÄúI‚Äôve a theory that one can always get anything one wants if one will pay the price. And do you know what the price is, nine times out of ten? Compromise. A beastly thing, compromise, but it steals upon you as you near middle age. It‚Äôs stealing upon me now. To get the woman I want I‚Äôd‚ÅÝ‚ÄîI‚Äôd even take up regular work.‚Äù

Virginia laughed.

‚ÄúI was brought up to a trade, you know,‚Äù continued Anthony.

‚ÄúAnd you abandoned it?‚Äù

‚ÄúYes.‚Äù

‚ÄúWhy?‚Äù

‚ÄúA matter of principle.‚Äù

‚ÄúOh!‚Äù

‚ÄúYou‚Äôre a very unusual woman,‚Äù said Anthony suddenly, turning and looking at her.

‚ÄúWhy?‚Äù

‚ÄúYou can refrain from asking questions.‚Äù

‚ÄúYou mean that I haven‚Äôt asked you what your trade was?‚Äù

‚ÄúJust that.‚Äù

Again they walked on in silence. They were nearing the house now, passing close by the scented sweetness of the rose garden.

‚ÄúYou understand well enough, I dare say,‚Äù said Anthony, breaking the silence. ‚ÄúYou know when a man‚Äôs in love with you. I don‚Äôt suppose you care a hang for me‚ÅÝ‚Äîor for anyone else‚ÅÝ‚Äîbut, by God, I‚Äôd like to make you care.‚Äù

‚ÄúDo you think you could?‚Äù asked Virginia, in a low voice.

‚ÄúProbably not, but I‚Äôd have a damned good try.‚Äù

‚ÄúAre you sorry you ever met me?‚Äù she said suddenly.

‚ÄúLord no. It‚Äôs the red signal again. When I first saw you‚ÅÝ‚Äîthat day in Pont Street, I knew I was up against something that was going to hurt like fun. Your face did that to me‚ÅÝ‚Äîjust your face. There‚Äôs magic in you from head to foot‚ÅÝ‚Äîsome women are like that, but I‚Äôve never known a woman who had so much of it as you have. You‚Äôll marry someone respectable and prosperous, I suppose, and I shall return to my disreputable life, but I‚Äôll kiss you once before I go‚ÅÝ‚ÄîI swear I will.‚Äù

‚ÄúYou can‚Äôt do it now,‚Äù said Virginia softly. ‚ÄúSuperintendent Battle is watching us out of the library window.‚Äù

Anthony looked at her.

‚ÄúYou‚Äôre rather a devil, Virginia,‚Äù he said dispassionately. ‚ÄúBut rather a dear too.‚Äù

Then he waved his hand airily to Superintendent Battle.

‚ÄúCaught any criminals this morning, Battle?‚Äù

‚ÄúNot as yet, Mr.¬ÝCade.‚Äù

‚ÄúThat sounds hopeful.‚Äù

Battle, with an agility surprising in so stolid a man, vaulted out of the library window and joined them on the terrace.

‚ÄúI‚Äôve got Professor Wynward down here,‚Äù he announced in a whisper. ‚ÄúJust this minute arrived. He‚Äôs decoding the letters now. Would you like to see him at work?‚Äù

His tone suggested that of the showman speaking of some pet exhibit. Receiving a reply in the affirmative, he led them up to the window and invited them to peep inside.

Seated at a table, the letters spread out in front of him and writing busily on a big sheet of paper was a small red-haired man of middle age. He grunted irritably to himself as he wrote, and every now and then rubbed his nose violently until its hue almost rivalled that of his hair.

Presently he looked up.

‚ÄúThat you, Battle? What you want me down here to unravel this tomfoolery for? A child in arms could do it. A baby of two could do it on its head. Call this thing a cipher? It leaps to the eye, man.‚Äù

‚ÄúI‚Äôm glad of that, Professor,‚Äù said Battle mildly. ‚ÄúBut we‚Äôre not all so clever as you are, you know.‚Äù

‚ÄúIt doesn‚Äôt need cleverness,‚Äù snapped the Professor. ‚ÄúIt‚Äôs routine work. Do you want the whole bundle done? It‚Äôs a long business, you know‚ÅÝ‚Äîrequires diligent application and close attention, and absolutely no intelligence. I‚Äôve done the one dated ‚ÄòChimneys‚Äô which you said was important. I might as well take the rest back to London and hand ‚Äôem over to one of my assistants. I really can‚Äôt afford the time myself. I‚Äôve come away now from a real teaser, and I want to get back to it.‚Äù

His eyes glistened a little.

‚ÄúVery well, Professor,‚Äù assented Battle. ‚ÄúI‚Äôm sorry we‚Äôre such small fry. I‚Äôll explain to Mr.¬ÝLomax. It‚Äôs just this one letter that all the hurry is about. Lord Caterham is expecting you to stay for lunch, I believe.‚Äù

‚ÄúNever have lunch,‚Äù said the Professor. ‚ÄúBad habit, lunch. A banana and a water biscuit is all any sane and healthy man should need in the middle of the day.‚Äù

He seized his overcoat, which lay across the back of a chair. Battle went round to the front of the house, and a few minutes later Anthony and Virginia heard the sound of a car driving away.

Battle rejoined them, carrying in his hand the half-sheet of paper which the Professor had given him.

‚ÄúHe‚Äôs always like that,‚Äù said Battle, referring to the departed Professor. ‚ÄúIn the very deuce of a hurry. Clever man, though. Well, here‚Äôs the kernel of Her Majesty‚Äôs letter. Care to have a look at it?‚Äù

Virginia stretched out a hand, and Anthony read it over her shoulder. It had been, he remembered, a long epistle, breathing mingled passion and despair. The genius of Professor Wynward had transformed it into an essentially businesslike communication.

Operations carried out successfully, but S. double crossed us. Has removed stone from hiding-place. Not in his room. I have searched. Found following memorandum which I think refers to it: ‚ÄúRichmond Seven Straight Eight Left Three Right.‚Äù

‚ÄúS.?‚Äù said Anthony. ‚ÄúStylptitch, of course. Cunning old dog. He changed the hiding-place.‚Äù

‚ÄúRichmond,‚Äù said Virginia thoughtfully. ‚ÄúIs the diamond concealed somewhere at Richmond, I wonder?‚Äù

‚ÄúIt‚Äôs a favourite spot for royalties,‚Äù agreed Anthony.

Battle shook his head.

‚ÄúI still think it‚Äôs a reference to something in this house.‚Äù

‚ÄúI know,‚Äù cried Virginia suddenly.

Both men turned to look at her.

‚ÄúThe Holbein portrait in the Council Chamber. They were tapping on the wall just below it. And it‚Äôs a portrait of the Earl of Richmond!‚Äù

‚ÄúYou‚Äôve got it,‚Äù said Battle, and slapped his leg.

He spoke with an animation quite unwonted.

‚ÄúThat‚Äôs the starting-point, the picture, and the crooks know no more than we do what the figures refer to. Those two men in armour stand directly underneath the picture, and their first idea was that the diamond was hidden in one of them. The measurements might have been inches. That failed, and their next idea was a secret passage or stairway, or a sliding panel. Do you know of any such thing, Mrs.¬ÝRevel?‚Äù

Virginia shook her head.

‚ÄúThere‚Äôs a Priest‚Äôs Hole, and at least one secret passage, I know,‚Äù she said. ‚ÄúI believe I‚Äôve been shown them once, but I can‚Äôt remember much about them now. Here‚Äôs Bundle, she‚Äôll know.‚Äù

Bundle was coming quickly along the terrace towards them.

‚ÄúI‚Äôm taking the Panhard up to town after lunch,‚Äù she remarked. ‚ÄúAnyone want a lift? Wouldn‚Äôt you like to come, Mr.¬ÝCade? We‚Äôll be back by dinnertime.‚Äù

‚ÄúNo, thanks,‚Äù said Anthony. ‚ÄúI‚Äôm quite happy and busy down here.‚Äù

‚ÄúThe man fears me,‚Äù said Bundle. ‚ÄúEither my driving or my fatal fascination! Which is it?‚Äù

‚ÄúThe latter,‚Äù said Anthony. ‚ÄúEvery time.‚Äù

‚ÄúBundle, dear,‚Äù said Virginia, ‚Äúis there any secret passage leading out of the Council Chamber?‚Äù

‚ÄúRather. But it‚Äôs only a mouldy one. Supposed to lead from Chimneys to Wyvern Abbey. So it did in the old, old days, but it‚Äôs all blocked up now. You can only get along it for about a hundred yards from this end. The one upstairs in the White Gallery is ever so much more amusing, and the Priest‚Äôs Hole isn‚Äôt half bad.‚Äù

‚ÄúWe‚Äôre not regarding them from an artistic standpoint,‚Äù explained Virginia. ‚ÄúIt‚Äôs business. How do you get into the Council Chamber one?‚Äù

‚ÄúHinged panel. I‚Äôll show you after lunch if you like.‚Äù

‚ÄúThank you,‚Äù said Superintendent Battle. ‚ÄúShall we say at 2:30?‚Äù

Bundle looked at him with lifted eyebrows.

‚ÄúCrook stuff?‚Äù she inquired.

Tredwell appeared on the terrace.

‚ÄúLuncheon is served, my lady,‚Äù he announced.

XXXI

Sundry Details

Scene—Chimneys, 11 a.m. Thursday morning.

Johnson, the police constable, with his coat off, digging.

Something in the nature of a funeral feeling seems to be in the air. The friends and relations stand round the grave that Johnson is digging.

George Lomax has the air of the principal beneficiary under the will of the deceased. Superintendent Battle, with his immovable face, seems pleased that the funeral arrangements have gone so nicely. As the undertaker, it reflects credit upon him. Lord Caterham has that solemn and shocked look which Englishmen assume when a religious ceremony is in progress.

Mr. Fish does not fit into the picture so well. He is not sufficiently grave.

Johnson bends to his task. Suddenly he straightens up. A little stir of excitement passes round.

“That’ll do, sonny,” says Mr. Fish. “We shall do nicely now.”

One perceives at once that he is really the family physician.

Johnson retires. Mr. Fish, with due solemnity, stoops over the excavation. The surgeon is about to operate.

He brings out a small canvas package. With much ceremony he hands it to Superintendent Battle. The latter, in his turn, hands it to George Lomax. The etiquette of the situation has now been fully complied with.

George Lomax unwraps the package, slits up the oil-silk inside it, burrows into further wrapping. For a moment he holds something on the palm of his hand—then quickly shrouds it once more in cotton wool.

He clears his throat.

“At this auspicious minute,” he begins, with the clear delivery of the practised speaker.

Lord Caterham beats a precipitate retreat. On the terrace he finds his daughter.

“Bundle, is that car of yours in order?”

“Yes. Why?”

“Then take me up to town in it immediately. I’m going abroad at once—today.”

“But, father—”

“Don’t argue with me, Bundle. George Lomax told me when he arrived this morning that he was anxious to have a few words with me privately on a matter of the utmost delicacy. He added that the king of Timbuktu was arriving in London shortly. I won’t go through it again, Bundle, do you hear? Not for fifty George Lomaxes! If Chimneys is so valuable to the nation, let the nation buy it. Otherwise I shall sell it to a syndicate and they can turn it into an hotel.”

“Where is Codders now?”

Bundle is rising to the situation.

“At the present minute,” replied Lord Caterham, looking at his watch, “he is good for at least fifteen minutes about the Empire.”

Another picture.

Mr. Bill Eversleigh, not invited to be present at the graveside ceremony, at the telephone.

“No, really, I mean it. … I say, don’t be huffy. … Well, you will have supper tonight anyway? … No, I haven’t. I’ve been kept to it with my nose at the grindstone. You’ve no idea what Codders is like. … I say, Dolly, you know jolly well what I think about you. … You know I’ve never cared for anyone but you. … Yes, I’ll come to the show first. How does the old wheeze go? ‘And the little girl tries, hooks and eyes.’ …”

Unearthly sounds. Mr. Eversleigh trying to hum the refrain in question.

And now George’s peroration draws to a close.

“… the lasting peace and prosperity of the British Empire!”

“I guess,” said Mr. Hiram Fish sotto voce to himself and the world at large, “that this has been a great little old week.”